<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Womenintech on Ilona Who Codes</title>
    <link>//www.ilonacodes.com/tags/womenintech/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Womenintech on Ilona Who Codes</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="//www.ilonacodes.com/tags/womenintech/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Ada Lovelace Festival 2017 in Berlin</title>
      <link>//www.ilonacodes.com/blog/ada-lovelace-festival-2017-in-berlin/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Oct 2017 07:00:05 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//www.ilonacodes.com/blog/ada-lovelace-festival-2017-in-berlin/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The last week I have attended Ada Lovelace Festival that occurred on 19-20 October 2017. The aim of the event to connect women in computing and technology.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, I was a bit too late for the keynote, because I had a lecture at the university. However, I joined the conference, and after registration, I got my bag with sponsors gifts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For example, a pen and a paper notebook from the WirtschaftsWoche, and a small car model and candies from Porsche. I was a quite pleased. Of course, I also grabbed a few relevant stickers for my laptop.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Below, I would like to list the talks and a workshop that I have found pretty inspiring for me as a woman in tech.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first speech &lt;code&gt;Talent: The tools we need to build a digital nation of signification&lt;/code&gt; by Jacqueline de Rojas, techUK was about the importance of smart and intelligent people in the tech industry.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The future turns digital. That means people keep up with the times, taking into consideration all the software industry aspects.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;//www.ilonacodes.com/blog/images/ada-lovelace-1.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Photo-1&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next workshop, that gave me valuable tips and pointed out some ways how to grow your brand called &lt;code&gt;To be in the 1st row: Build your own brand&lt;/code&gt; by Regina Mehler, WOMEN SPEAKER FOUNDATION.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The speaker showed us the importance of networking, communication, and negotiation with top-brass people at occasional meetings, using examples from their career. The workshop finished with a practical session between participants.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;//www.ilonacodes.com/blog/images/ada-lovelace-2.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Photo-2&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a web developer, I couldn&amp;rsquo;t pass the talk &lt;code&gt;How to improve our technical decision-making skills&lt;/code&gt; by Duana Stanley, Clue. All developers know that the core skill of problem-solving is to find useful information quickly and to be able to make a decision based on the reliable information and requirements.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Firstly, the speaker defined what a right technical decision is. Such decision takes context into account. Then speaker has described the process in which developers should:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;understand the decision,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;check their emotions,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;list and evaluate options,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;build consensus and&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;sleep on it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;//www.ilonacodes.com/blog/images/ada-lovelace-3.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Photo-3&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At this point, I’m going to finish the post. I have tried to share my impression from the Ada Lovelace Festival 2017 in Berlin with you, dear Techmakers. I hope you enjoyed the highlights of the event from my point of view.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wish you a great week and new achievements.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>