<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Inspiration on Ilona Who Codes &amp; UXs</title>
    <link>//www.ilonacodes.com/tags/inspiration/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Inspiration on Ilona Who Codes &amp; UXs</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 20 Aug 2018 06:00:05 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="//www.ilonacodes.com/tags/inspiration/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>The perfect home office setup for work</title>
      <link>//www.ilonacodes.com/blog/the-perfect-home-office-setup-for-work/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Aug 2018 06:00:05 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//www.ilonacodes.com/blog/the-perfect-home-office-setup-for-work/</guid>
      <description>&lt;figure&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;//www.ilonacodes.com/blog/images/the-perfect-home-office-setup-for-work-cover.jpeg&#34; /&gt;
    
    
    &lt;figcaption&gt;
        &lt;h4&gt;source: https://www.pexels.com/photo/apple-devices-books-business-coffee-572056/&lt;/h4&gt;
        
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;I know most people cannot work productively at home. Someone finds it difficult to organize themselves. Others can’t make the right schedule to work at home. For others, the work environment at home (or a cafe) is just not optimized for work in general.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, now I want to describe the ideal setup that inspires me to be productive work at home. Find my most essential tips below on how to set up a productive home office:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ada Lovelace Festival 2017 in Berlin</title>
      <link>//www.ilonacodes.com/blog/ada-lovelace-festival-2017-in-berlin/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Oct 2017 07:00:05 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//www.ilonacodes.com/blog/ada-lovelace-festival-2017-in-berlin/</guid>
      <description>The last week I have attended Ada Lovelace Festival that occurred on 19-20 October 2017. The aim of the event to connect women in computing and technology.
Unfortunately, I was a bit too late for the keynote, because I had a lecture at the university. However, I joined the conference, and after registration, I got my bag with sponsors gifts.
For example, a pen and a paper notebook from the WirtschaftsWoche, and a small car model and candies from Porsche.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>React.js &amp; React Native Meetup at Home24 in Berlin</title>
      <link>//www.ilonacodes.com/blog/react-meetup-at-home24-berlin/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Oct 2017 08:30:05 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//www.ilonacodes.com/blog/react-meetup-at-home24-berlin/</guid>
      <description>Hey, there! In this blog post, I’m going to share my impression about the React.js &amp;amp; React Native meetup in Berlin that I have visited at Home24 yesterday.
If you still didn&amp;rsquo;t have a look at the topic of my blog, so, as you noticed from the title, I am interested in front-end development and at the moments specialized in the JavaScript language and especially in React framework.
Close to the point, I would like to tell you a couple of words about the last meetup.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>